ANURAG SINGH

Software Engineer

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience in developing web applications majorly in Frontend Development part of the applications. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

07/2022 - Present

Anthology Inc

Bengaluru, India

- Successfully converted whole project from AngularJS to ReactJS, and also the part of the support and maintenance team to fix the bugs.
- Worked on a team of 26 member on Learn-Ultra product of Blacboard Inc using technologies like ReactJS, Redux, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3 etc...
- Scripted unique test plans, test scripts and processes to remove previously known redundancy by 40% and ensured predictable outcomes
- Implemented functionalities such as course selection, payment functionalities in Learn-Ultra and marks.
- Collaborated effectively with team members to achieve target results within the specified timeframe, ensuring successful project completion.

Software Developer

09/2021 - 06/2022

Coforge Ltd

Bengaluru, India

- Moved the automation solution into a commercial software of the back office banking application which is developed in ReactJS, JavaScript, C#, MVVM, Asp.Net.
- Designed and developed reusable software components which used in 3 different project with reducing development effort by the huge margin.
- Contributed to the initial setup and development of E-commerce project, laying the foundation for its functionality and features.
- Successfully optimized a news/media website, improving its performance and user experience.
- Worked on the GoNiyo Banking Application Development using technologies like ReactJs, Next.js, Redux etc.... Also integrated the Razorpay payment gateway API and was responsible for page authorisation and validation.
- Developed and implemented responsive news/media websites, ensuring seamless display across various devices and screen sizes.
- Created reusable code components, following best practices and coding standards, resulting in more efficient and maintainable codebase.

Associate Software Engineer

2013 - 2015

MealFi Pvt Ltd (Client)

Austin, TX

- Worked on the official web application of its Frontend Development part using ReactJS, Redux, RESTFul APIs. Also designed the UI/UX of the app using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Adobe, Figma etc...
- Contributed on whole lot of application's sections on technologies like HTML,CSS,JavaScript, Bootstrap etc...
- Improved user interfaces by updating menus to be more intuitive, increasing sales by 5%
- Performed root cause analysis for more than 10 issues to identify bugs and rolled out fixes to production within 2 days.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

06/2016 - 06/2020

Maulana Abul Kalam Azad University of Technology

Kolkata, India

Higher Secondary

06/2013 - 06/2015

Shaheed Shashi Prasad Singh Mahavidyalaya

Patna, India

ACHIEVEMENTS

Have been a part of \$12M software project.

from design to distribution as a software engineer in a 16-member team

Web Development Bootcamp (11/2020 - 12/2020)

Web Design Graphic Design & Illustration Design Tools User Experience .Made me continue to learn and grow as a developer.

SKILLS

Tools

Java · JavaScript · C# · ReactJS · HTML5 ·

CSS3 · SCSS · Tailwind CSS · MaterialUI ·

Redux · Flux · Adobe · Figma · UI/UX ·

Bootstrap · XML · Typescript · Next.js ·

Express.is · Vue.is · Node.is · mongoDB ·

JIRA · Django · Agile Methodology ·

Docker · RESTful API ·

Software Development · Python ·

React Native •

Data Structure & Algorithm

Operating Systems

MacOS · Linux · Windows

STRENGTHS

🚖 Student Sahayak Award

Was awarded the trophy for 4 years of consecutive excellet work in the field of Student Sahayak Program (2016-2020)

★ Corporate Social Responsibility

Volunteered in the NSS team for my college, organized tuition platforms for the underprivileged. Designed confluence page for book drives, etc.

